- ♪ In the not too distant
Future ♪
♪ Somewhere in time and space ♪
♪ Mike Nelson
And his robot pals ♪
♪ Are caught in a nasty place ♪
♪ They try to survive
The wrath of Pearl ♪
♪ Just an evil gal
Who wants to rule the world ♪
♪ From her castle below
She sets her sights above ♪
♪ Just to torture
All the captives ♪
♪ On the Satellite of Love ♪
MIKE:
Get Me Down!
- ♪ I'll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst I can find
La la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
And watch them all ♪
♪ And I'll monitor his mind
La la la ♪
- ♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies begin or end
La la la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ With the help
Of his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call
Cambot! ♪
- ♪ Gypsy! ♪
- ♪ Tom Servo! ♪
SERVO: Check me out.
- ♪ Croooooow! ♪
- ♪ If you're wondering how
He eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La la la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
"It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000" ♪
Hi, everyone. Welcome
to the Satellite of Love.
Mike Nelson here,
along with Gypsy,
Crow T. Robot...
- Hi.
- ...and Servo.
- It-- it's Serveaux.
- Yeah, that's what I said,
Servo.
- Oh, no.
See, I changed my name.
It's not Servo anymore,
it's Sirveaux.
It sounds the same, only
it's spelled S-I-R-V-E-A-U-X,
"Sirveaux." Well, just grab
that visual aid down there.
- Okay.
- So, you want us to call you
Sirveaux from now on?
- Yeah, I'd prefer it.
- What if we called you Servo?
- I won't respond.
- Hmm.
- Anyway, we'll be right back.
- Oh, oh, and I added an H
to my first name,
so you can call me...
- Oh, okay, let me guess.
It's T-H-O-M, Thom.
- Oh, no, no.
The H is at the beginning,
so it's Htom.
- Well, Htom,
why don't you hlick me?
- Ooh, that's a good one!
- Okay.
Sorry about this.
We'll be right back.
[♪♪♪]
- No, no, no.
It's Croe.
- Croeee.
- It's very simple: Croe.
- Croee.
Krr?
- No, no, no.
Purse your beak, Mike.
- Krrw. Krrw.
Oh, Pearl's calling.
I'll purse your beak!
- Krw.
- Stop it.
- My friends, this is it.
Future generations
may damn me,
but in moments,
the world will be mine,
for I have created
a mutant virus
so insidious,
yet so destructive
that by morning,
half the planet's population
will be dead.
[GROWLING]
MIKE:
Never mind that.
Find the lady!
Come on, let's go.
Find the lady.
- Fool!
This is no time for games.
You will be the first to die.
- Never mind that.
Find the lady.
Come on, find the lady.
It's easy.
Anyone can do it.
Find the lady.
Nothin' to watch,
a buck to play.
Find the lady.
- Don't you see
that I have the power to...
kill... uh, the middle one.
The middle one!
- Sorry.
Costs a buck to play.
Come on now.
Find the lady.
- Okay, here's a buck.
- It's a setup.
You can't win.
It's a setup.
- Shut up.
Um, the left.
- No! I'm sorry.
Here she is.
Come on, now.
Find the lady.
Easy to do.
Come on.
Let's play.
- [GROWLING]
Llllll--
right.
- You are exactly... wrong!
Here she was.
Okay, Pearl, let's raise
the stakes a little bit.
Now, if we win, we get to choose
the movie we watch.
If you win,
we'll watch two movies.
Now, you think
you can take me?
Go ahead on.
It's your move.
- Okay, Nelson, I pick...
- Pick the middle!
Pick the middle.
No, wait.
It's the left.
No, right! Right!
Right!
It's the right one.
Wait, wait.
It's the queen.
The queen is the lady, right?
- Drink this.
- Oh, okay.
- Milk bag, you're omniscient.
What do you think?
- It's a scam.
You can't win.
- Oh, I forgot.
You're also a puss.
I pick middle.
- Hmm, yes, yes.
Let's see.
Yes, yes, yes...
- No!
- We win!
We get any movie we want.
- Mike, you're da bomb, man.
What are you gonna pick?
- Oh, let's see.
Something I like.
Say, the greatest drama
of all time.
Pearl, send me Hamlet...
...Branagh, Zeferelli,
Olivier, it's your choice.
- [WHISPERING]
... Hamlet...
[indistinct]
... German...
... bratwurst...
- [GIGGLING]
Perfect.
You win.
Fine.
You get Hamlet.
Oh, boy do you get Hamlet!
A dark, dreary dubbed version
made in 1960
for German television.
[GIGGLING]
God am I good!
- Girlie,
you are the best.
- Send it up, Cream Cheese and
choke it down, schnitzel box.
[ALL GROANING]
- We won. Follow the...
wrong...
uh... we...
- Put it away, honey.
Come on.
- Time for starchy,
pork-filled German Hamlet.
[BUZZING]
- Movie sign!
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Ooh, look at that.
♪ Umlaut shoobee
doobee daa hmm hmm ♪
SERVO:
If there's a Reich Furher,
I'm leaving.
CROW:
That means this version
is deep-fried
and served with spaetzle.
[FOOTSTEPS]
MIKE:
San Quentin Prison
presents Shakespeare.
SERVO:
God! There's going
to be railing kills.
Hee hee hee hee!
[FOOTSTEPS]
CROW:
Why am I not getting results
from my power walks?
MIKE:
Is that Hamlet?
CROW:
No, that's his friend Riblet.
[FOOTSTEPS]
SERVO:
♪ Brush up your Shakespeare
Hmm hmm hmm hmm ♪
- Halt! Who's there?
Stand and unfold yourself.
- Long live the King.
- Bernardo?
- Himself.
MIKE:
Wow, good thing
he unfolded himself.
He was pretty creased
up there.
- 'Tis bitter cold
and I'm sick at heart.
- Have you had quiet guard?
- Not a mouse stirring.
CROW:
Use my head as a toilet brush.
- Halt, who's there?
MIKE:
Unstaple yourself.
- Friend to this ground
and liegemen to the Dane.
- Is Horatio there?
- A piece of him.
SERVO:
I have his pancreas
in my pocket.
Hey, any Danish left?
Heh heh heh.
MIKE:
So, uh, how's the play going?
- What?
CROW:
I didn't say anything.
- Has this thing appeared
again tonight?
- I have seen nothing.
- Horatio says
'tis but our fantasy,
and will not let belief
take hold of him
touching this dreaded sight,
twice seen of us.
- Tush, tush,
'twill not appear.
- Last night of all,
Francisco and myself,
the bell then beating one.
SERVO:
You're getting a ticket!
- In the same figure,
like the King that's dead.
MIKE:
And, uh, get your head
off my head.
- It would be spoke to.
- Horatio, speak to it.
SERVO:
His royal majesty, Rip Taylor!
- What art thou...
CROW:
Moe, Larry, and Horatio.
- ...that usurps
this time of night...
MIKE:
Oh, it's probably Bob
usurping this time of night.
- ...together with that fair
and warlike form
in which the majesty of buried
Denmark did sometimes march?
SERVO:
Woob woob woob woob woob!
- Stay!
Speak!
I charge thee, speak!
I'll cross
it though it blast me.
- Stay, illusion!
CROW:
Ladies and gentlemen,
Patti LaBelle!
- If thou hast any sound
or use of voice, speak to me.
If there be any good thing
to be done that may to thee
do ease and grace to me,
speak to me.
MIKE:
I don't think so, breeder.
SERVO:
Hell?
- Stop it, Francisco!
CROW:
He's headed
for the Ladies' Room!
- 'Tis here!
[SERVO SCREECHING]
MIKE:
Let us to brunch.
- 'Tis gone.
CROW:
Cute, though.
SERVO:
What?
- How now, Horatio?
Something is rotten
in the state of Denmark.
MIKE:
Yeah, I didn't have
any clean pantaloons
or hose this morning.
- Break we our watch up,
and by my advice
let us impart
what we have seen tonight
unto young Hamlet,
for upon my life,
this spirit,
dumb to us, will speak to him.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
♪ Night fever night fever
We know how to do it... ♪
[♪♪♪]
CROW: To be or...
SERVO: No, no! Not yet.
CROW:
Oh, sorry.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Hey, how ya doing, Debbie?
CROW:
When Danish flirting falls flat.
SERVO:
Your loss, babe.
[MIKE SPITTING]
SERVO:
So? I don't even care.
MIKE:
Oh! Someone dropped a sardine.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Censors were shocked
by the blatant carnality
in this film.
[SERVO CHUCKLING]
SERVO:
Her card tricks
really aren't that impressive
with sleeves like that now.
MIKE:
Wow.
- Though yet of Hamlet
our dear brother's death
the memory be green,
and that it us befitted
to bear our hearts in grief
and our whole kingdom,
yet so far hath discretion
fought with nature
that we with wisest sorrow
think on him,
together with remembrance
of ourselves.
MIKE:
That's enough, Claude.
- Therefore,
our sometime sister...
SERVO:
Oh, baby!
- ...now our queen...
SERVO:
Juicy got me crazy!
- ...have we, as 'twere,
with a defeated joy -
with an auspicious
and a drooping eye,
with mirth in funeral
and with dirge in marriage
in equal scale weighing
delight and dole -
taken to wife.
CROW:
Gertrude's hair by Bozo.
- Nor have we herein
barred your better wisdoms,
which have freely
gone with this affair along.
For all, our thanks.
MIKE:
Try the Vienna sausages.
CROW:
Stepdad, will you help me
with my science fair project?
- And now, Laertes,
what's the news with you?
You told us of some suit.
What is it, Laertes?
What wouldst thou beg
that shall not be my offer,
not thy asking?
What wouldst thou have,
Laertes?
SERVO:
Let me check with my lawyer.
- My lord, your leave and favor
to return to France,
from whence, though willingly,
I came to Denmark to show
my duty in your coronation,
yet now I must confess,
that duty done,
my thoughts and wishes
bend again towards France
and bow them to your
gracious leave and pardon.
- Have you
your father's leave?
What says Polonius?
- I do beseech you,
give him leave to go.
SERVO:
Huh! How do you even
rule this clown?
- Laertes, time be thine.
Take thy fair hour
and spend it at they will.
MIKE:
Tsk! Ring-licker.
SERVO:
Tonight I'm gonna unleash
the great Dane!
Heh heh.
- But now, my cousin Hamlet,
and my son...
MIKE:
You're not my real dad.
- A little more than kin,
and less than kind.
CROW: [GASPS]
That's from Hamlet, isn't it?
[FOOTSTEPS]
- Hamlet, how is it
that the clouds
still hang on you?
- Not so, my lord.
I am too much in the sun.
SERVO: [COUGHS]
Incest.
MIKE:
Honey, can you get mommy
a fresh margarita?
CROW:
Face it, son.
I'm gonna rock
your uncle's world.
- Let not thy mother
lose her prayers, Hamlet.
MIKE:
Trollope. I mean, what?
- I pray thee, stay with us.
Go not to Wittenberg.
SERVO:
There's plenty of good
state schools here.
- I shall in all my best
obey you, madam.
- Good.
'Tis a loving and a fair reply.
MIKE:
Now go mow the lawn.
- Be as ourself in Denmark.
CROW:
Eww, your breath
smells like Havarti.
- Come, madam.
SERVO:
We'll be on the throne.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Okay, closing time, people.
Back door out.
- Oh, that this too,
too solid flesh would melt,
thaw, and resolve itself
into a dew,
or that the Everlasting
had not fixed his cannon
'gainst self-slaughter.
Oh, God!
How weary, stale,
flat, and unprofitable
seem to me
all the uses of the world.
Fie!
'Tis an unweeded garden.
Things rank and gross
possess it merely.
That it should come to this!
But two months dead.
Nay, not so much; not two.
SERVO:
Wait. Is it Saturday today?
- So excellent a king,
that was to this Hyperion
to a satyr,
so loving to my mother
that he might not
beteem the winds of heaven
visit her face too roughly,
and yet within a month...
MIKE:
I don't know.
Maybe it's just me.
- Frailty, thy name is woman.
CROW:
I thought Frailty's name
was Carl.
- A little month...
SERVO:
Oh! Didn't see the post there.
- ...or ere those shoes
were old with which
she followed
my poor father's body,
like Niobe, all tears.
Why she - Oh, god!
A beast that wants
discourse of reason
would have mourned longer.
Within a month,
ere yet the salt
of most unrighteous tears
had left the flushing in her
galled eyes, she married.
CROW:
Plus, she's marrying
Uncle Creepy.
- Oh, wicked speed
to post with such dexterity
to incestuous sheets!
It is not nor it cannot
come to good.
MIKE:
Well, I'd better go get
that Fieldcrest blanket
they registered for.
- But break, my heart,
for I must hold my tongue.
- Hail to your lordship.
- Good evening, sir.
CROW:
You can brood here. I'm done.
- Horatio!
CROW:
How's it hanging,
you son-of-a...?
Gee!
- My good friend, what make
you here from Wittenberg?
- A truant disposition,
good my lord.
- I would not hear
your enemy say so.
I know you are no truant.
But what is your affair
in Elsinore?
We'll teach you to drink
deep ere you depart.
- I came to see
your father's funeral.
- I pray thee, do not mock me,
fellow-student.
I think it was to see
my mother's wedding.
- Indeed, my lord,
it followed hard upon.
MIKE:
So, it worked out all right.
- Thrift, Horatio!
Thrift.
The funeral baked meats
did coldly furnish forth
the marriage tables.
Would I had met
my dearest foe in heaven
or ever I had seen that day,
Horatio.
My father!
- He was a goodly king.
SERVO:
I mean, he tried.
- He was a man.
Take him for all in all,
I shall not look upon
his like again.
CROW:
Why were you lookin'
at his like?
- My lord...
I think I saw him
yesternight.
- Saw who?
- My lord, the king,
your father.
- The king, my...
for God's love,
let me hear!
- And these few precepts
in thy memory
give thy thoughts no tongue.
SERVO:
Oh, he's memorizing
Tim Allen's book.
- Give thy thoughts no tongue
nor any unproportioned
thought his act.
MIKE: Hi, Pops!
CROW: It's a swell day!
- Yet here, Laertes?
SERVO:
Observe my lice.
- A double blessing
is a double grace.
- Aboard, aboard!
The wind sits
in the shoulder of your sail
and you are stayed for.
MIKE:
Dad likes me better.
- Now these few precepts
in thy memory:
give thy thoughts no tongue
nor any unproportioned
thought his act.
CROW:
Wow. This place could use
a shrub or, hell,
even a stick
would cheer it up.
MIKE:
Hey, come on, man.
We've seen,
like, eight ghosts.
None of them have been
even close to my dad.
- What hour now?
SERVO:
Time for you to buy a watch.
- I think it lacks of twelve.
- No, it is struck.
- Indeed?
CROW:
The great "what time is it"
argument from Hamlet.
- Then it draws near
the season wherein
the spirit
held his wont to walk.
SERVO:
You got that right, buddy.
[CHUCKLES]
MIKE:
Trick or treat for nipples.
[♪♪♪]
- What does this mean, my lord?
SERVO:
And now, My Little Margie.
- The king...
CROW:
The big number one.
- ...doth wake tonight,
takes his rouse, keeps wassail,
and the swaggering
upspring reels,
and as he drains his draughts
of Rhenish down,
the kettledrum and trumpet
thus bray out
the triumph of his pledge.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Let there be Sunny D
for everyone!
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Oh, they hired
the all-fanfare DJ.
CROW:
Hooray! Garrison Keillor's
leaving Denmark!
ALL:
Yay!
SERVO:
Hee hee! I got a stick.
Hee hee!
- My lord, it comes.
CROW:
Scrooge! Oh, wrong story.
MIKE:
Meet the Beatles.
- Angels and ministers
of grace defend us.
SERVO:
Move thine ass.
- It beckons you
to go away with it.
- But do not go with it!
- No! By no means.
- Why?
What would be the fear?
I do not set my life
at a pin's fee and for my soul,
what can it do to that,
being a thing
immortal as itself?
It waves me forth again.
I'll follow it.
- You shall not go, my lord.
- Hold off your hands.
My fate cries out.
Unhand me, by heaven.
I'll make a ghost
of him that lets me.
CROW:
Yeah, get him, Ham.
Kick his ass!
SERVO: Go!
CROW: Alright!
MIKE:
Now, this is an action scene
for this movie.
SERVO:
Oh, he's doing the
"I was told to report
to the Principal's office" walk.
CROW:
I'm on my way
to a costume party.
I'm going as Rosalind Russell.
[FOOTSTEPS]
- Whither would thou lead me?
Speak.
I'll go no further.
MIKE:
That's not what I hear,
Sunshine.
- Speak.
[SERVO BARKING]
- I am bound to hear.
- So art thou to revenge
when thou shalt hear.
- What?
- I am thy father's spirit.
CROW:
I've got a bit of the flu.
- But that I am forbid to tell
the secrets of my prison-house,
I could a tale unfold
whose lightest word
would harrow up thy soul.
But this eternal blazon
must not be
to ears of flesh and blood.
MIKE:
Camera two!
Cut to camera two!
- List, list, oh, list!
CROW:
Dress for less?
Did I...?
- If thou didst ever
thy dear father love...
- Oh, heaven!
- ...revenge his murder.
- Murder!
- Murder most foul.
CROW: He killed a chicken?
- Haste me to know it
that I, with wings
as swift as meditation
or the thoughts of love,
may sweep to my revenge.
- 'Tis given out that,
sleeping in my orchard,
a serpent stung me...
SERVO:
Cut to the ghost.
The ghost!
Cut to the ghost!
- ...thy father's life
now wears his crown.
- Oh, my prophetic soul!
My uncle.
- Aye, that incestuous beast
won to his shameful lust
the will of my most
seeming-virtuous queen.
CROW:
That's what I am.
- Sleeping within my orchard
upon my secure hour,
thy uncle stole
with juice of cursed hebenon
in a vial and in the porches of
my ears...
CROW: To the ghost!
- ...poured leprous distilment.
MIKE:
Oh, hang on.
I'm passin' a stone. Ooh.
- Thus was I, sleeping,
by a brother's hand of life...
SERVO:
Oh, boy, this
"ghost of Mike's father"
gag is too good!
CROW:
Yep, no question,
a brilliantly conceived,
perfectly executed
bit of tomfoolery.
- Hello?
SERVO: Aaah! A ghost! Help me!
CROW:
Servo, it's just Mike.
SERVO:
Oh, okay.
[COUGHS]
Mark me,
for I am your father's ghost
come to tell you...
- Whoa, wait a minute.
No. Can't be my father.
He's alive and well.
Owns a mail-order burlap store
out in Minong, Wisconsin.
SERVO:
D'oh! We didn't check on that.
Ugh. Okay, okay,
try his Uncle Les.
I'm pretty sure he's dead.
CROW:
I'm your Uncle Les, come to...
- Oh, no, no. Retired.
Lives in McAllen, Texas.
You know, Pearl just forwarded
another of his delightful
Christmas letters.
SERVO:
Cousin Al! Cousin Al!
CROW:
Okay. I'm your cousin Al,
dead more these two months...
- Oh, no, no.
He's alive.
He rebuilds carburetors
out of a pole shed
in Sauk Rapids, Minnesota.
Just sent me a price list.
You know, you can
get a pretty good deal...
- Any leads there,
other part of the ghost?
SERVO:
Uh, uh, uh...
okay, okay, okay.
Brother-in-law's
ex-wife Wanda?
CROW:
Okay. I am your
brother-in-laws...
- Oh, no. Not Wanda.
She works a pit crew
up to Brainerd.
She can hurl a tire 35 feet
without even breathing hard.
CROW: [SIGHS]
Don't your relatives ever die?
It's over.
Hit it, Cousin Wanda.
SERVO:
First try his brother Ron's
karate teacher Herb Dowdy.
CROW: Put a sock in it.
SERVO: No! Let me go. Watch it!
CROW: You cut it out.
SERVO: Ow! Ow!
- We'll be right back.
[ALL YELLING]
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
It's supposed to be a duck.
CROW:
I love life.
Oh, yeah, that was hilarious.
Any way.
MIKE:
She stitched her hand
to her knee.
CROW: [GROWLING]
Mmm, friend, huh.
SERVO:
Oh, I stuck a fork
in the outlet.
MIKE:
How 'bout some
spiral-cut Hamlet?
CROW:
Get thee to a bakery.
No wait...
- [GASPS]
SERVO:
Ooh.
He's doing a Danish mind meld.
CROW:
Don't look.
It's your Christmas present.
MIKE:
Oh, man! Me and Horatio
got blasted on Aquavit,
woke up on the express bus
to Copenhagen.
Ugh.
SERVO:
What is it, boy?
Uncle killed dad?
Hmm?
MIKE:
Well, I'm gonna take off,
I guess.
So, okay then.
CROW:
Dad! Hamlet's looking at me.
- How now, Ophelia!
What's the matter?
- I have been so affrighted.
- With what,
in the name of God?
SERVO:
Your hair.
- As I was sewing in my closet,
my lord, Hamlet...
MIKE:
She was sewing in her closet?
- ...with his doublet all
unbraced, pale as his shirt,
his knees
knocking each other,
and with a look
so piteous in purport,
he comes before me.
CROW:
No one likes a tattletale,
Ophelia.
- Mad for thy love?
- My lord, I do not know,
but truly I do fear it.
SERVO:
I'm gonna get my hair re-lumped.
CROW:
Honey, what happened
to all the ear poison?
MIKE:
Boom!
SERVO:
Yeah.
CROW:
What is it,
Cold Water on the Groin...
I mean, Polonius?
- My lord, I do think
that I have found the very cause
of Hamlet's lunacy.
MIKE:
He's insane.
- Oh, speak of that.
That do I long to hear.
Thou still has been
the father of good news.
- Have I, my lord?
I assure my good liege.
I hold my duty
as I hold my soul
both to my God
and to my gracious king.
SERVO:
I know nothing.
- He tells me, my dear Gertrude,
he hath found
the source of
all your son's distemper.
- I doubt it is no other
but the main:
his father's death
and our o'er hasty marriage.
MIKE: Hi!
- My liege and madam,
your noble son is mad.
Mad call I it for to define
true madness what is't
but to be nothing else but mad.
- More matter with less art.
- Madam, I use no art at all.
That he is mad 'tis true.
'Tis true, 'tis pity,
and pity 'tis 'tis true.
Thus it remains...
CROW:
They had huge balance beams
back then.
Look at that.
MIKE:
Ah, she's logging names
into her Palm Pilot.
SERVO:
Honey, check this out.
'Ah, so. I Japanese.'
Huh! Sorry.
CROW:
Please pray for me
while I shower.
SERVO:
What the Shroud of Turin sees.
CROW:
The nuns sent me home.
My skirt is too short.
- Nymph, in thy orisons
be all my sins remembered.
MIKE:
Whoo!
The "orison" line
sucked the air out of the room.
[WHISTLES]
- My prince...
SERVO:
...are back from Photo Mat.
- How does your honor
for this many a day?
CROW:
I don't know.
Okay, I guess.
- I humbly thank you. Well.
MIKE:
But could you please
return my pants?
- My prince...
SERVO:
...didn't come out that well.
MIKE:
Ooh, the bench smells funny.
- ...I have remembrances
of yours
that I have longed long
to re-deliver.
I pray you now receive them.
- Not I.
I never gave you aught.
CROW:
Tcha!
- My honored prince, you know
right well you did...
SERVO:
Right well did not.
- ...in words
of so sweet breath composed
as made the things more rich,
their perfume lost.
Take these again,
for to the noble mind
rich gifts wax poor
when givers prove unkind.
There my lord.
MIKE:
Okay, fine.
I'll throw them away.
- Are you honest?
CROW: Yes. No. I lied!
- My lord?
- Are you fair?
- What means your lordship?
- That if you be
honest and fair,
your honesty should admit
no discourse to your beauty.
- Could beauty
have better commerce,
my prince, than with honesty?
- Aye, truly...
CROW:
Yeah, you know, what you said.
- ...for the power of beauty
will sooner transform honesty
from what it is to a bawd
than the force of honesty
can translate beauty
into his likeness.
This was sometime a paradox,
but now the time
gives it proof.
MIKE:
Huh? What do you think
of them apples?
[SPITTING]
- I did love you once.
- Aye, my prince.
You made me believe so.
- You should not have
believed me.
I loved you not.
MIKE:
Well, I always thought
you were gay.
- I was the more deceived.
- Get thee to a nunnery.
Why wouldst thou be
a breeder of sinners?
CROW:
Be a breeder of schnauzers.
- I am myself indifferent
honest,
but yet I could accuse me
of such things
that it were better
my mother had not borne me.
I am very proud,
revengeful, ambitious.
SERVO:
Ooh, he's Republican.
- We are errant knaves, all.
Believe none of us.
MIKE:
Can you set me up with Horatio?
CROW:
Heh! I shut her down, man.
- [WHISPERING]
Where's your father?
SERVO: [WHISPERING]
Bastard owes me ten kronors.
- At home, my lord.
CROW:
Ophelia, Sam Wainwright's
on the phone!
- Let the doors
be shut upon him
that he may play the fool
nowhere but in his own house!
[SOBBING]
MIKE:
Whoa. Jackson Browne-let.
[SOBBING]
CROW:
Thank you, but I don't need CPR.
Thank you.
[GASPING]
- If thou dost marry,
I'll give thee
this plague for thy dowry:
be thou as chaste as ice,
as pure as snow,
thou shall not escape calumny.
Get thee to a nunnery.
Go! Farewell!
SERVO:
You're doing fine, honey!
He's all yours.
You got him.
[GASPING, SOBBING]
- Or if thou wilt needs marry,
marry a fool
for wise men know well enough
what monsters you make of them.
To a nunnery go. Farewell!
MIKE:
Gah!
Just gets my tights in a bundle.
- Oh, heavenly powers
restore him!
- I've heard of your paintings
too, well enough.
God has given you one face
and you make yourselves another.
You jig, you amble,
and you lisp,
you nickname God's creatures...
and make your wantonness
your ignorance.
Go to, I'll no more on't.
It hath made me mad.
That hath made me mad!
CROW:
I'm not here!
- I say we will have
no more marriages.
Those that are married,
all - all but one
- shall long live.
The rest shall
keep as they are.
CROW:
I am back. You miss me?
- To a nunnery go.
MIKE:
Well, actually,
I may go to grad school.
- [SOBBING]
Oh, what a noble mind
is here o'er thrown.
The courtier's, soldier's,
scholar's eye,
tongue, sword, expectancy
and rose of the fair state!
Glass of fashion
and the mould of form all down.
Oh, woe!
MIKE:
Whoa!
- Woe is me to have seen what
I have seen,
see what I-- what I see.
[SOBBING]
SERVO:
Thank you for cooperating
with the Copenhagen police.
You can take off the wire now.
- How now, Ophelia?
You did not tell us
what Lord Hamlet said.
We heard it all.
- He's far gone.
Far gone.
And truly in my youth
I suffered much extremity
for love very near this.
- Love?
CROW: Here? Now?
- No, his affections
do not that way tend,
nor what he speak,
though it lacked form a little,
was not like madness.
- I'll speak to him.
MIKE:
I'm just gonna run
to the pop machine first.
[♪♪♪]
SERVO:
Rap artist Notorious K-I-N-G.
[FOOTSTEPS]
CROW:
Hi, I'm an Oliver Reed stand-in.
- Woe is me...
SERVO:
Woe is me!
- ...to have seen
what I have seen...
MIKE:
Mary Pickford as Ophelia.
- ...see what I see.
CROW:
Stupid, stupid Hamlet!
What was I thinking?
SERVO:
Hey, Kilroy!
- To be or not to be?
MIKE:
The verbal equivalent of
♪ Dun dun dun daaa ♪
- That is the question.
CROW:
I'll take "To Be"
for fifty, Alex.
- Whether 'tis
nobler in the mind
to suffer the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune...
SERVO:
Starring Shelley Long
and Bette Middler.
- ...or to take arms
against a sea of troubles,
and by opposing, end them.
MIKE:
Ow! My shin's right on
the edge of a stair.
Oh!
- To die...
to sleep.
CROW:
Yeah, that's what we're doin'
right now, bub.
- No more...
and by a sleep to say
we end the heartache
and the thousand natural shocks
that flesh is heir to...
MIKE:
Okay, we need a predicate now.
- ...'tis a consummation
devoutly to be wished.
CROW:
Especially with Ophelia, man!
[ALL CHUCKLING]
- To die...
to sleep...
SERVO: To sleeeep!
MIKE: Whoa!
CROW:
That's an old chestnut.
- ...to sleep...
SERVO: [WHISPERING]
To sleeeep!
MIKE: [CHUCKLING]
Okay.
- ...a chance to dream.
CROW:
...the impossible dream!
- Aye, there's the rub!
MIKE:
I knew I had some rub left.
- For in that sleep of death,
what dreams may come
when we have
shuffled off this mortal coil
must give us pause.
There's the respect that
makes calamity of so long life,
for who would bear
the whips and scorns of time,
the oppressor's wrong,
the proud man's contumely,
the pangs of despised love,
the law's delay,
the insolence of office,
and the spurns that patient
merit of the unworthy takes
when he himself might his
quietus make with a bare bodkin?
CROW: [CHUCKLING]
He said bare bodkin!
[ALL CHUCKLING]
- Who would fardels bear...
MIKE:
Fardels!
- ...to grunt and sweat under
a weary life
but that the dread
of something after death,
the undiscovered country from
whose bourn
no traveler returns
puzzles the will
and makes us rather bear
those ills we have
than fly to others...
SERVO:
Sum up!
- ...that we know not of?
Thus conscience does make
cowards of us all,
and thus the native hue
of resolution
is sicklied o'er
with the pale cast of thought,
and enterprises
of great pith and moment
with this regard
their currents turn awry
and lose the name of action.
MIKE:
So, I'm a chicken
for not stabbing myself.
That's all you needed to say!
SERVO: D'oh!
CROW: Oh!
MIKE:
Whoa!
SERVO:
What's worse than clowns?
Danish clowns.
CROW:
Danish clowns, the damp, smelly,
silverfish-infested basement
of the clown world.
[SERVO CHUCKLING]
MIKE:
Okay, out. Out! Out!
All of you, get out.
You, get out! Out!
[♪♪♪]
SERVO:
It's a herd of Hamlets!
CROW:
We can't get rid of them.
It's hopeless.
SERVO:
It's Hamlet Man!
CROW:
Daa daa daa daaaa!
- Welcome, masters.
Welcome all.
CROW:
Except you, condom-hat there.
[FOOTSTEPS]
- I am glad to see you well.
Welcome good friends.
SERVO:
Nice to see
the Hostess Sno Balls.
- Old friend,
thy face is valanced
since I saw thee last.
- [CHUCKLING]
- What, my young lady!
Your ladyship...
MIKE:
How's lesbianism going?
- ...is nearer to heaven
by the altitude of a chopine
than when I saw you last.
Pray God, your voice
like a piece of uncurrent gold
be not cracked within the ring.
- I hope not so, my lord.
- Welcome all.
We'll e'en to it
like French falconers,
fly at anything we see.
We'll have a speech straight.
Come, give us a taste
of your quality.
CROW:
I said 'quality' not 'idiocy.'
[♪♪♪]
- Well?
A passionate speech.
SERVO:
Come here. We gotta talk.
- Can you play
The Murder of Gonzago?
- Aye, my lord.
- We'll have
that tomorrow night.
You could, for a need...
CROW:
Lose the clowns.
- ...study a speech
of some dozen or 16 lines,
which I would set down
and insert in it.
Could you not?
CROW: Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Aye, my lord.
- Very well.
MIKE:
Yeah,
and I want Elizabeth Berkeley
to play the lead, okay?
[♪♪♪]
- That's an excellent idea.
- Well, thank you.
- Hey, where have you guys been?
I haven't
seen you around at all.
- Oh, sorry Mike.
We've been in the middle
of rehearsals
for our own version of Hamlet.
It's gonna be sort of a modern
abstract interpretation
sort of thing, you know.
- Oh, so kind of
like the works
of Richard Schechner
or Heiner Muller
or, well,
countless college troupes.
- Oh, yeah.
It's a timeless drama, Mike.
Everyone should
take a shot at it.
- Yeah, there's just so many
ways
to render the play, Mike.
- We even got as far as
story boarding a few ideas.
- Now, Mike, help us out there.
Would you get those?
- Yeah, sure.
- Now, here's what
we came up with
for our scuba diving version.
Pretty powerful stuff, huh?
SERVO:
Then we considered
a bucket-head Hamlet.
CROW:
The buckets, of course,
symbolizing modern man's
faceless conformity.
SERVO:
Yeah, but it didn't
really pan out.
Well, then we were right
in the middle of rehearsals
with our all-furniture version.
- Oh, we were having
so much fun!
The sofa that was playing
Gertrude was a delight!
- Yes, but then our backers
pulled out just days
before the opening.
The footstools
were pretty upset.
- Well, I think
all the furniture was.
- Yeah, they were.
But-- but that brings us
to our percussion version
of Hamlet.
The bongos here
represent Ophelia.
- And obviously,
these maracas are Hamlet.
Now, allow us to perform
a part of Act III, Scene 1.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
[DRUMMING]
[RATTLING]
[SERVO GRUNTING]
[BUZZING]
- Oh, excuse me...
we got movie sign.
We can pick this up later.
- We're just getting
to the murder, Mike.
Hang on.
CROW:
Now is the winter of our...
Damn, wrong play.
- About, my brains!
CROW:
Upon which I sit. [CHUCKLING]
- I'll have these players
play something like
the murder of my father
before mine uncle.
I'll observe his looks,
I'll tent him to the quick.
If he but blench,
I'll know my course.
MIKE:
If he but parboil, well...
- The spirit that I've seen
may be a devil
and perhaps out of my weakness
and my melancholy
abuses me to damn me.
I'll have grounds
more relative than this.
SERVO:
He should start journaling.
- The play is the thing...
CROW:
A badda badda badda bing.
- ...wherein I'll catch
the conscience of the king.
SERVO:
A ring-a-ding ding ding ding.
MIKE:
Let's see.
Boy, girl, boy, girl, me.
Okay.
CROW:
Whoa! The dinner rush is here.
Look lively, people.
MIKE:
It's the slow-walking race.
In the front,
Lillian and Bob are losing.
SERVO:
Listen.
The Hamlets always have
a kick-ass party table.
MIKE:
Yeah!
[CROW HUMMING]
CROW:
Um, they can see you, Hamlet.
MIKE:
Oh, shoot.
Frank Rich is out there.
- Come! 'Tis ready.
SERVO:
We have a small
but spirited house.
- Horatio!
- Here, sweet lord,
at your service.
CROW:
Good. Go wash my car.
- There's a play tonight
before the king.
One scene of it
comes near the circumstance
which I've told you
of my father's death.
With the very comment
of thy soul,
observe mine uncle.
If his occulted guilt
do not unkennel in one speech,
it is a damned ghost
that we have seen.
SERVO:
I suppose there's no chance
there's going to be
a jet ski chase
in this movie, is there, Mike?
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Look!
Polonius is riding in my sleeve.
MIKE:
Ick. Mom's wearing Arpege.
I can smell it from here.
SERVO:
And now, live from Elsinore...
CROW:
I guess. Heh-heh.
[APPLAUSE]
MIKE:
Hey, how's everyone
doing tonight?
Good to see ya.
Hey! I need a volunteer
from the audience.
- Come hither, my dear Hamlet.
Sit by me.
SERVO:
Thanks, my hose-bag...
I mean, mom.
- No, good mother.
Here's metal more attractive.
CROW:
You are made out of metal,
right Ophelia?
MIKE:
Did you hear that?
Totally dusted my mom.
- Lady,
shall I lie in your lap?
- No, my prince.
- I mean my head in your lap.
- Aye, my prince.
CROW:
Okay, now it's just creepy.
Forget it.
- Do you think
I meant country matters?
- I think nothing, my prince.
CROW:
Shakespeare blue!
- That's a fair thought,
to lie between maids' legs.
- What is, my prince?
MIKE:
A complete perv.
- Nothing.
- You are merry, my prince.
- Who, I?
- Aye, my prince.
- Oh God!
Your only jig-maker.
What should a man do
but be merry,
for look you how cheerfully
my mother looks,
and my father died
within these two hours.
- Nay, 'tis twice
two months, my prince.
- So long?
SERVO:
Is that 32, Mike?
- Die two months ago
and not forgotten yet?
CROW:
We totally rule, man!
MIKE:
Run DMC Everett Koop!
- For us and for our tragedy,
here stooping to your clemency,
we beg your hearing patiently.
- Is this a prologue
or the posy of a ring?
- 'Tis brief, my prince.
- As a woman's love.
SERVO:
And now,
the tragedy of King Vita Man.
- Full thirty times...
ALL:
Boo! You suck!
Off the stage! Boo!
- ...and Tell us' orbed ground,
since love our hearts
and Hymen did our hands unite
co-mutual in most sacred bands.
- So many journeys
may the sun...
MIKE:
Let's sneak out
for some cabaret.
CROW:
I think so!
- ...but woe is me,
you are so sick of late,
so far from cheer
and from your former state
that I distrust you.
Yet, though
I distrust, discomfort you,
my lord, it nothing must.
...For women's fear
and love...
SERVO:
Go!
- ...in neither aught or...
SERVO: Rock it!
CROW:
Take it home now! Do it!
- Faith, I must leave thee,
love, and shortly too.
My operant power
their functions leave to do
and thou shalt live
in this fair world behind...
SERVO:
The hell?
MIKE:
A production
that likes to show
people watching other people.
- Oh, confound the rest!
Such love must needs
be treason in my breast.
In second husband
let me be accursed.
SERVO:
I think it's pretty funny.
- None wed the second
but who killed the first.
- That's wormwood.
SERVO:
It is not wormwood.
Would you shut up?
- ...marriage move
are base respects of thrift,
but none of love,
nor earth to give me
food nor heaven light.
Sport and repose
lock from me day and night.
MIKE:
Man, at least
they get to drink at The Globe.
- Hence pursue me
lasting strife,
if once a widow
ever I be wife.
- If she should...
CROW: Shhh!
You'll be
unwrapping candies next.
- Sweet, leave me here awhile.
My spirits grow dull and faint
I would beguile
the tedious day with sleep.
SERVO:
My geometrically perfect
neck boils are hurting.
- ...and never come
mischance between us twain.
[APPLAUSE]
MIKE:
Great! Good droning.
Excellent!
CROW:
Entertainment was much easier
back then, Mike.
[APPLAUSE]
- Madam,
how like you this play?
- [CHUCKLING]
The lady doth
protest too much, methinks.
- Oh?
But she'll keep her word.
- Have you heard the argument?
Is there no offence in it?
- No, no. They do but jest,
poison in jest,
no offence in the world.
MIKE:
Hey, there's gum back here.
- What do you call the play?
- The Mousetrap.
[SERVO HUMMING]
[CROW SPITTING]
- This play's the image
of a murder done in Vienna.
You shall see anon
'tis a knavish piece of work.
But what of that?
Your majesty and we
that have free souls,
it touches us not.
Let the galled jade wince,
our withers are un wrung.
[CROW CHUCKLING]
- This one is Lucianus,
nephew to the king.
Begin, murderer!
Leave thy damnable faces
and begin.
CROW:
Anyway, enjoy the show.
- The croaking raven
doth bellow for revenge.
- Thoughts black, hands apt,
drugs fit, and time agreeing.
Confederate season,
else no creature seeing.
[CROW SNICKERING]
- Thou mixture rank
of midnight weeds collected,
with Hecate's ban...
MIKE:
Woof! He's eatin' it.
- ...infected.
Thy natural magic
and dire property
on wholesome life
usurps immediately.
- He poisons him
in the garden for his estate.
His name's Gonzago.
The story is extant and
written in very choice Italian.
You shall see anon
how the murder
gets the love of Gonzago's wife.
SERVO:
You get it? Huh? Huh?
You get it?
Huh?
- Lights! Lights!
MIKE:
Camera! Soliloquy!
- What,
frightened with false fire?
CROW:
Careful with that,
I have a ton of Final Net
in my hair.
MIKE:
Can't I pee in peace?
- I like him not...
CROW:
I like him. Not!
- ...nor stands it safe with us
to let his madness range...
SERVO:
With rich Corinthian leather.
- ...therefore, prepare you.
I you commission
will forthwith dispatch...
MIKE:
Yeah, but I'm drawing
against commission.
- ...and he to England
shall along with you.
The terms of our estate
may not endure hazards
so near as doth hourly grow
out of his brain.
CROW:
Now, which one of you
is Squiggy?
- Arm you, I pray you,
to this speedy voyage.
CROW:
Scram! Beat it.
MIKE:
They gotta be gay.
- For we will fetters put about
this fear which now goes
too free-footed.
SERVO:
Yeah! [CHUCKLING]
- My good lord!
CROW:
I'm out of styling mousse.
- He's going
to his mother's closet.
Behind the arras I'll convey
myself to hear the process.
Fare you well my liege.
Ere you go to bed,
I'll call upon you
and tell you what I know.
SERVO:
I saw this
on Three's Company once.
- Thanks dear my lord.
CROW:
Um, he's already gone.
MIKE:
To be or not...
Oh, sorry.
CROW:
Wrong character.
- Oh, my offence is rank.
SERVO:
Yeah, your tunic's rank too.
Woof!
- It smells to heaven.
It hath the primal
eldest curse upon it...
a brother's murder.
CROW:
Somehow,
I feel partially responsible.
- Pray, can I not...
though inclination
be as sharp as will.
SERVO:
Wheaton.
- My stronger guilt
defeats my strong intent.
CROW:
Huh. I must be Catholic.
- And like a man
to double business bound,
I stand in pause
where I should first
begin and both neglect.
What if...
CROW:
Nah, that'll be
like the fifth time today.
- ...if this cursed hand
were thicker than itself
with brother's blood?
SERVO:
Well, thin it
with a little chicken stock.
- Is there not rain enough
in the sweet heavens
to wash it white as snow?
CROW:
Uh, hey, the clowns
need their money.
Can I get a check?
- Oh, what form of prayer
can serve my turn...
MIKE:
Oh, what fun it is to ride.
- ...forgive me my foul murder?
CROW:
It's just, that turkey
was mouthing off to me.
- That cannot be,
since I am still possessed
of those effects
for which I did the murder:
my crown, my own ambition,
and my queen.
SERVO:
My Queen albums, I mean.
- May one be pardoned
and retain the offence?
- Now might I do it but pat...
CROW:
This play's losing me.
Now who's Pat?
- He is praying.
And now I'll do it.
SERVO:
I'm just going
to lightly stab him.
[CHUCKLING]
MIKE:
Nosferatu!
CROW:
Wow! My uncle's got a great ass.
No wonder mom's into him.
SERVO:
You know, he's just beating back
a monologue right now.
CROW:
Oh yeah.
- And so he goes to heaven,
and so am I revenged.
Oh, this is hire and salary,
not revenge.
When he is drunk asleep
or in his rage
or the incestuous pleasure
of his bed,
then trip him that his heels
may kick at heaven
and his soul may be
as damned and black as hell
whereto it goes.
MIKE:
Damn, I'm interesting.
- My mother stays.
This physic but prolongs
thy sickly days.
SERVO:
That's Sickly Days,
downtown Copenhagen.
CROW:
I'll come back later,
see if he's drinkin'
and whorin'.
Then I'll kill him.
SERVO:
♪ Doo dee dee doo da dum ♪
- Tell him his pranks have been
too broad to bear with
and that your grace
has screened
and stood between
much heat and him.
SERVO:
Hogan!
- I'll silence me in here
and shall overhear his speech.
Pray you, be round with him.
- Mother!
MIKE:
You used my razor.
- I'll warrant you,
fear me not.
Withdraw.
He is coming.
SERVO:
Fran Allison,
Queen of Denmark.
CROW:
She's got Maude wear on.
MIKE:
Hey! Your occasional chair
just found an occasion.
SERVO:
Hmm! Whatdya know!
- Now, mother,
what's the matter?
- Hamlet, thou hast thy father
much offended.
- Mother, you have my father
- Come, come.
You answer with an idle tongue.
- Go, go. You question
with a wicked tongue.
- Why, how now, Hamlet?
- What's the matter now?
SERVO:
Don't you sass me
or you're grounded.
- Have you forgotten me?
- No, by the rood!
You are the queen,
your husband's brother's wife
and -
would it were not so -
you are my mother.
- Good.
I'll set those to you
that can speak.
- Come!
CROW: Let's tango!
- You shall not budge.
You go not
'til I set you up a glass
where you may see
the inmost part of you.
- What wilt thou do?
Thou will not murder me.
Help! Help!
- Help! Help!
- How now?
A rat?
MIKE:
No! No!
Not the Service Master guy!
Ooh.
- Dead!
SERVO: Shame.
Dead, for a ducat. Dead!
- What hast thou done?
- Nay, I know not.
Is it the king?
- Oh, what a rash
and bloody deed is this!
- Aye, a bloody deed.
Almost as bad, good mother,
as kill a king
and marry with his brother.
CROW:
Oh, bring that up again.
- As kill a king?
- Aye, t'was my word.
MIKE:
[indistinct] my son.
SERVO: [CHOKING]
Oh, the candied sardines
are repeating on me.
- Thou wretched, rash,
intruding fool.
CROW:
Oh, right.
It's my fault you killed me.
- I took thee for thy better.
Take thy fortune.
MIKE:
Well, we need a new Polonius.
[FOOTSTEPS]
SERVO:
That was the royal antechamber.
Stay together, people.
There's the throne room.
Oh, and we're in luck.
The king's here.
CROW:
Couldst thou walk slower?
Geez!
- Now, Hamlet...
MIKE:
About your report card.
- ...where is Polonius?
- At supper.
- At supper?
Where?
- Not where he eats
but where he's eaten.
A certain convocation of
politic worms are even at him.
[CHUCKLING]
SERVO:
Ooh, mood swing.
- Your worm is your only emperor
for diet.
A man may fish with the worm
that hath eat of a king
and eat of the fish
that fed of that worm.
- What dost thou mean by this?
- Nothing but to show you
how a king
may go a progress
through the guts of a beggar.
That is the end.
CROW:
That was directed at me,
wasn't it?
MIKE:
Get the belt.
- Where is Polonius?
SERVO:
He came down
with an unexpected
case of murder.
- In heaven.
Send thither to see.
If your messenger
find him not there,
seek him yourself
in the other place.
MIKE:
H-E double toothpicks.
- But indeed, if you find him
not within this month...
CROW:
King Richard Thompson.
- ...you shall nose him
as you go up the stairs
into the lobby.
MIKE:
♪ Let's go up to the lobby... ♪
- Go. Seek him there.
- He will stay till you come.
SERVO:
Oh! Ice cream headache.
Woof!
Ow! Ow!
[SOBBING]
MIKE:
He just started his estrogen.
CROW:
Hey, come on you wuss.
I didn't cry
after I killed your dad.
- Hamlet...
SERVO: Yeah?
[SOBBING]
- For thine special safety
which we do tender...
SERVO:
Uh huh?
- ...as we dearly grieve
for that which thou hast done...
SERVO: Okay.
[SOBBING]
- ...must send thee hence
with fiery quickness.
SERVO:
Quickness.
- Prepare thyself.
The bark is ready
and the wind at help.
The associates tend
and everything
is bent for England.
SERVO:
Bent for England?
[SOBBING]
- For England.
- Aye, Hamlet.
- Good.
- So is it if thou knewest
our purposes.
- I see a cherub...
CROW:
In thy nose.
- ...that sees them.
Come, for England.
SERVO:
Oh, I'll need some money.
- Goodnight, dear mother.
- Thy loving father, Hamlet.
- My mother.
Father and mother
is man and wife,
man and wife is one flesh,
and so my mother.
MIKE:
Ugh, yeah.
Go a lot to England, okay?
- Come! For England.
CROW:
Rrawr!
[FOOTSTEPS]
SERVO:
Would you just get over there?
[FOOTSTEPS]
MIKE:
Those thrones need some
Lime-A-Way.
SERVO:
Hi, guys. Where's my dad?
[FOOTSTEPS]
MIKE:
Hail, Queen Dilbert's Boss.
CROW:
What, is he dressing up
for Charlie Sheen?
SERVO:
Taa daa!
Ooh!
- Oh, thou vile king!
Give me my father.
MIKE:
Oh, my goodness.
- Where are my Switzers?
- Good Laertes!
Calmly!
- Let him go.
CROW:
Your mother's drunk. Sorry.
- Yet we do not
fear our person.
SERVO:
Yum! Dane kebabs.
- There is such divinity
doth hedge a king
that treason can but peep
to what it would
acts little of his will.
Tell me, Laertes,
why are thou thus incensed?
Let him go, Gertrude.
Speak, man.
- Where's my father?
- Dead.
- But not by him.
- Let him demand his fill.
- How came he dead?
I'll not be juggled with.
CROW:
I'm not a small sack of beans.
- To hell, allegiance.
Vows to the blackest devil.
I dare damnation.
To this point I stand,
that both the worlds
I give to negligence,
let come what comes,
only I'll be revenged
most thoroughly for my father.
- Who shall stay you?
SERVO:
Don't tell him that, you idiot!
- Good Laertes,
if you desire to know
the certainty
of your dear father,
is writ in your revenge
that swoop stake you will draw
both friend and foe,
winner and loser?
- None but his enemies.
- Ah!
Now you speak like a good child
and a true gentleman.
That I am guiltless of your
father's death, Laertes...
MIKE:
He's wearing dental x-rays
around his neck.
- ...and am most sensible
in grief for it.
It shall as level
to your judgment pierce
as day does to your eye.
CROW:
Okay, Gertrude! Tackle him!
SERVO:
New King Claudius
with kung fu grip.
MIKE:
Whoo! Get the net, huh?
- ♪ They bore him barefaced
On the bier ♪
CROW:
Oh, no. It's Jewel.
Get her out of here.
- ♪ Hi diddle doo ♪
SERVO:
♪ I've got a brand new pair
Of roller skates ♪
- ♪ And in his grave
Rained many a tear ♪
MIKE:
She's totin' around
a big bok choy.
- ♪ Fare you well my dove ♪
[HUMMING]
CROW:
She's trying to Section 8
her way out of the movie.
[HUMMING]
- By heaven!
Thy madness shall be paid
by weight.
SERVO:
So, about 110 pounds of madness?
- Beloved sister...
MIKE:
He looks like a cheerleader
for a Southern football team.
- ...hadst thou thy wits
and didst persuade revenge
it could not move thus.
- There's rosemary.
SERVO:
And Maury Amsterdam.
- That's for remembrance.
Pray you, my love, remember.
And there's pansies.
That's for thoughts.
CROW:
Try to get one. Ha ha!
People love my wheat act.
[HUMMING]
SERVO:
Huh? Oh, yeah,
you're gluten intolerant.
Hmm.
- There's fennel
for you and columbines.
We may call it
herb-o-grace on Sundays.
There's rue for you
and some for me.
MIKE:
No, really, I ate before I came.
- Oh, you must wear
your rue with a difference.
[CHUCKLING]
[CROW BABBLING]
- I would give you some violets,
but they withered all
when my father died.
They say he made a good end.
And will he not come again?
MIKE:
Uh-huh. Hey,
what do you have in a rye?
- And will he not come again?
SERVO:
So, you didn't take
your Zoloft, huh?
[CHUCKLING]
He is gone.
He is gone
and we cast away moan.
God have mercy on his soul
and of all Christian souls,
I pray God.
God be with you.
[HUMMING]
- Do you see this?
Oh God.
MIKE:
I'm going over
to Lady MacBeth's.
- Laertes, I must commune
with your grief...
SERVO:
Would you stop
rubbing my nipples?
- ...or you deny me right.
Make choice from
your wisest friends you will
and they shall judge
twixt you and me...
CROW:
Don't get a boner.
- ...and where the offence is,
let the great axe fall.
MIKE:
So we're going to chop wood.
Do you have to be so dramatic?
- There's a letter
for you, sir.
It came from the ambassador
that was bound for England.
MIKE:
Um, there's postage due.
SERVO:
Ophelia invoiced me
for the wheat!
- 'Ere we were
two days old at sea,
a pirate
of very warlike appointment
gave us chase.
Finding ourselves
too slow of sail,
we put on compelled valor
and in the grapple
I boarded them on the instant
they got clear of our ship
so I alone
became their prisoner.
CROW:
Hamlet faxed me a soliloquy.
- They have dealt
with my like thieves of mercy,
but they knew what they did.
Let the king
have the letters I have sent
and repair thou to me as quickly
as thou wouldst fly death.
These good fellows...
MIKE:
Hmm, I don't know about that.
- ...will bring thee
where I am.
I have words to speak
in thine ear
will make thee dumb.
Farewell.
He that thou knowest thine,
Hamlet.
SERVO:
I could crap a better letter
than this.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Oh, man!
I just played handball.
Oh!
CROW:
My contacts are fine.
- Laertes...
your sister is drowned.
- Drowned, you say?
Where?
SERVO:
Well, she jumped in a lake
trying to save some wheat.
- There is a willow
grows aslant a brook
that shows his hoar leaves
in the glassy stream.
There did she come
with fantastic garlands...
MIKE:
So, the creek?
Hey! Hey, do I rock
the Slurpee machine
when you're trying to work?
- How long will a man lie
in the earth ere he rot?
- Sir, if he be not rotten
before he die,
he will last you some
eight or nine year.
SERVO:
Bleh bleh bleh bleh bleh...
- A tanner will
last you nine year.
- Why he more than another?
- Why sir, his hide
is so tanned with his trade
that he will keep out water
a great while...
...and your water
is a sore decayer
of your whoreson dead body.
Here's a skull...
CROW:
Not a bad skull.
Good starter skull.
- ...now has lain in the earth
three and twenty years.
SERVO:
Bleh bleh bleh...
- Whose was it?
- A pestilence on him
for a mad rogue!
CROW:
Why I oughtta...!
- Poured a flagon
of Rhenish on my head once.
[CHUCKLING]
[MIKE CHUCKLING]
- This same skull, sir,
was Sir Yorick's skull,
the king's jester.
- This?
MIKE:
I just saw him
at the Chuckle Hut.
- Aye, aye.
E'en that.
- Let me see.
CROW:
Mmm! Nice zygomatic arch.
SERVO:
I remember him
in his big, pointy shoes,
stupid hat.
He had the worst act, I swear.
- Alas, poor Yorick.
MIKE:
Hey, I did alright for myself.
- I knew him, Horatio.
CROW:
I sat next to him in Trig.
- A fellow of infinite jest...
...of most excellent fancy.
He hath borne me on his back
a thousand times.
SERVO:
'Course I bored him a lot too.
Heh heh.
- And now how abhorred
in my imagination it is.
MIKE:
Wait.
This isn't Yorick,
this is George Gobel.
- Here hung those lips
that I have kissed
I know not how oft.
CROW:
You're a little cutie pie skull,
aren't you,
with your button nose?
You little cutie skull.
- Where be your jibes now?
You gamboled...
SERVO:
So they banned you from jesting.
- Your songs?
Your flashes of merriment
that were wont
to set the table on a roar?
Not one now
to mock your own grinning.
MIKE:
Well, there was that one mouth
that mocked it.
- Quite chap fallen.
Now get you
to my lady's chamber
and tell her
let her paint an inch thick,
to this favor she must come.
Go.
Make her laugh at that.
CROW:
Uh, please speak up.
My tympanic membrane
rotted away some years ago.
- Horatio, tell me one thing.
Dost thou think Alexander
looked 'o this fashion
in the earth?
SERVO:
I don't know, man.
Let's go to the tavern.
- E'en so.
- And smelled so?
MIKE:
Always did too. Huh!
- E'en so.
CROW:
Ah, forget it. I never knew him.
I made it all up.
- To what base uses
we return, Horatio.
SERVO:
My god, that's not dirt!
- Why may not imagination
trace the noble dust
of Alexander
'til he find it
stopping a bung-hole?
MIKE: Dude!
CROW: Right.
- 'Twere to consider too
curiously to consider so.
- No. No.
Alexander died,
Alexander was buried,
Alexander returneth to dust,
dust is earth,
of earth we make loam...
SERVO:
Tch! Yeah.
- ...and why of that loam,
whereto he was converted,
might they not stop
a beer barrel?
[BELL RINGING]
CROW:
It's the ice cream man!
SERVO:
Here comes my cow.
I gotta go.
[APPLAUSE]
- Hello and welcome
to "Alas Poor Who?"
Now as you know,
last week our reigning
champion, Mister Tom Servo,
won the fortnight's supply
of mutton
and he's back this week
to face another challenger.
[APPLAUSE]
- Thanks, Mike.
Thanks, everyone.
- Tom, remind the folks at home
what you do again.
- Mike, I am a small robot
who lives with you.
- Robot who lives with me.
That's interesting.
Okay, and your challenger,
Crow T. Robot.
How are you, sir?
- Ah, feelin' good, Mike.
Thanks.
- Mmm-hmm,
and what do you do, sir?
- I am also a small robot
who lives with you.
- Wow. Seems to be
a popular job these days.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[APPLAUSE]
- Let's get down to action.
Okay, for you folks at home,
the object of the game
is to visually identify
a person
by some part
of his or her skeletal system,
and Servo, you'll be starting
with this lovely femur.
Okay, you have ten seconds.
Go.
- Let's see.
Alas, poor Larry Hagman?
Oh, no, no.
Alas, poor Katherine Graham.
No.
Alas, poor... oh, shoot.
Oh, I got it!
Alas, poor Biz Markie.
[DINGING]
- Exactly!
Biz Markie!
[APPLAUSE]
This is his femur.
Surprisingly delicate,
isn't it?
[ALL LAUGHING]
Alright, well played.
Now, Crow,
you ready to give it a whirl?
- Oh, I sure am, Mike.
- Okay, then.
Here's a clavicle.
Whose is it?
- Wow. I wanna say Tim Conway,
but no,
more like Doctor Dean Ornish.
Uh, Germaine Greer,
Peter Cetera.
Geez. No, no!
I'm gonna go with
Nancy Allen, Mike.
- Please state it in
"Alas Poor" form.
- Oh, yeah.
Alas, poor Nancy Allen.
- Is right!
[DINGING]
- Yeah!
- That's a fine clavicle
she has there.
Must have drank lots of milk.
[ALL LAUGHING]
- Okay, it's all tied up.
Servo,
who belongs to this ileum?
- Oh, that's easy, Mike.
Alas, poor Alaska Senator
Ted Stevens.
Oh, oh, wait, no!
I'm sorry.
Alas, poor Roland Gift.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna go with
"Alas, poor Roland Gift."
[BUZZING]
- Ooh. No, I'm sorry.
Alas, poor Alaska Senator
Ted Stevens.
- Oh, darn.
[CHUCKLING]
- Close though.
Okay, Crow, now you
could win with this one so...
watch carefully.
Whose are these series
of metatarsal bones?
- Ooh! Ooh!
I know this one.
Easy.
Ralph Waite.
- They are indeed the
metatarsals of Ralph Waite...
- Yay!
- ...but, alas, incorrect form
for the second time...
[BUZZING]
...so you don't get the points
and so nobody wins
and you both lose...
...and that's all the time
we have. Ha ha!
[APPLAUSE]
We'll be back next week
with another edition
of "Alas, Poor Who?"
[APPLAUSE]
- Uh, Mike we won't really
be back
next week, will we?
- Not unless I get a codpiece.
[CHUCKLING]
[♪♪♪]
[BELLS TOLLING]
MIKE:
Ah! Saint Olaf's Day parade
is pretty dour this year.
SERVO:
Hey, kid, you wanna speed it up?
We got three of these today.
MIKE:
Ugh, I can barely
keep my head cake on.
- What ceremony else?
CROW:
Shut up.
- Her obsequies
have been as far enlarged
as we have warranty.
Her death was doubtful.
SERVO:
Well, shouldn't we check then?
- Must there no more be done?
- No more.
MIKE:
Gee, your tunic smells terrific.
SERVO:
Ah! With the legs.
We do not have time to take
a Beefeater to the hospital.
[BELLS TOLLING]
CROW:
Oh, man! I was invited to this.
I forgot.
- Farewell.
MIKE:
Wow.
That's really
an all-purpose dress.
- I hoped thou shouldst
have been my Hamlet's wife.
SERVO:
[MUMBLING]
- I thought thy bride-bed
to have decked, sweet maid...
[SERVO MUMBLING]
- ...and not have
strewed thy grave.
- Ophelia!
CROW:
I wonder what her skull is like.
- Hold off the earth awhile.
SERVO:
Stop the world.
I wanna get off.
Even in death,
he just goes in her room.
- Now pile your dust
upon the quick and dead
'til of this flat
a mountain you have made
to o'er top old Pelion...
CROW:
No!
- ...or the skyish head
of blue Olympus.
- What is he whose grief
bears such an emphasis,
whose phrase of sorrow
conjures the wandering stars
and makes them stand
like wonder-wounded hearers?
It is I,
Hamlet, the Dane.
The devil take thy soul.
I pray thee,
take thy fingers from my throat.
Hold off thy hand, I say.
- Pluck them asunder.
- Good my lord, be quiet.
SERVO:
This must be an Irish funeral.
They're both drunk and fighting.
- Why, I will fight with him
upon this theme
until my eyelids
will no longer wag.
I loved Ophelia!
MIKE:
We went steady!
- Forty thousand brothers
could not,
with all their quantity of love,
make up my sum.
MIKE:
Fifty thousand, maybe.
- What wilt thou do for her?
'Wounds,
show me what thou'llt do.
CROW:
Boomp, boomp.
SERVO:
I'm trying to be dead in here.
- Would weep?
Would fight?
Would fast?
Would tear thyself?
Would drink up
eisel or eat a crocodile?
I'll do it.
Dost thou come here to whine,
to outface me
with leaping in her grave?
MIKE:
He's getting German-er.
- Be buried quick with her
and so will I
and thou'lt mouth
I'll rant as well as thou.
- This is mere madness.
Oh, my son!
CROW:
Loser-tes!
SERVO: Crap-let!
- Hear you, sir.
What is the reason
that you use me thus?
I loved you ever...
MIKE:
Okay, was it her or me?
- ...but it is no matter.
The cat will mew and
dog will have his day.
CROW:
Pomeranian Day,
Dachshund Day,
Lhasa Apso Day.
SERVO:
Wait, wait! I'm supposed
to be in front of you.
Hold up.
MIKE:
Hey, Laertes,
lean on a headstone.
It's fun.
- Will you be ruled by me?
CROW:
Well,
I've got an attractive offer
from the king of Flanders.
- Aye, my lord, so you will not
overrule me to a peace.
- To thine own peace.
SERVO:
Hey, listen.
I've got some Cuban cigars, man.
- I will work him to an exploit
under the which he shall not
choose but fall
and for his death
no wind of blame
shall breathe
but even his mother shall
uncharged the practice
and call it accident.
- My lord, I will be ruled.
CROW:
Wide rule or college rule?
- The rather
if you could devise it so
that I might be the organ.
- It falls right.
SERVO:
Yes.
- What would you undertake
to show yourself
in deed more
your father's son than in words?
- To cut his throat
in the church.
MIKE:
Now, see, that's a little
over the top.
- No place indeed,
should murder sanctuarize.
Revenge should have no bounds.
But good Laertes,
we'll put on those
shall praise your excellence...
SERVO:
What about my church idea?
- ...and set a double varnish
on the fame,
bring you in fine together
and wager on your heads.
He, being free
from all contriving,
will not peruse the foils
so that with ease
or with a little shuffling
you may choose a sword un bated
and in a pass of practice
requite him for your father.
- I will do it.
CROW:
I'll cut his throat in a church.
- And for that purpose,
I'll anoint my sword.
MIKE:
Well, that's up to you.
- I bought an unction
of a mountebank.
SERVO:
Wow!
- I'll touch the point
with this contagion...
...that, if...
SERVO: Yes!
- ...I gall him slightly...
SERVO:
I'm getting it! Yes, yes.
Go on!
- ...it may be death.
CROW:
And cut his throat in a church.
SERVO:
No! Grr. Tch!
- If this should fail...
MIKE:
We're boned, man.
- I have it!
CROW:
Cut his throat in a church!
- When in your motion
you are hot and dry
as make your bouts more violent
to that end
and that he calls for drink,
I'll have prepared for him
a chalice for the nonce,
whereon but sipping,
if he by chance escape your
venomed stuck...
[CROW CHUCKLING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
- ...our purpose
may hold there.
SERVO:
Um, there's a phone call.
MIKE:
Cut his throat in a church.
I oughtta smack him.
CROW:
Would you just get over here?
[FOOTSTEPS]
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Group lice check.
CROW:
Hey, band's got a new song.
I like this song.
MIKE:
Yeah.
CROW:
Yeah!
SERVO:
I haven't gotten
my tax agenda yet.
Healthcare!
This Hamlet thing's
been tying me all up.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Synchronize royal asses
and... yes.
SERVO:
We decided to cut his throat
in a church.
CROW: [CHUCKLING]
Hello.
MIKE:
♪ This is the theme
To Hamlet Show! ♪
♪ The Hamlet Show theme! ♪
SERVO:
Good luck.
- Come.
Hamlet, come.
SERVO:
Sit, stay. Good Hamlet.
- Take this hand from me.
CROW:
Wipe spit on it, man.
Yeah.
MIKE:
Ha ha ha! Face!
- Give me your pardon, sir.
SERVO:
What are you, Nixon?
- I've done you wrong,
but pardoned as a gentleman.
This presence knows,
and you must needs have heard,
how I am punished
with a sore distraction.
What I have done
I here proclaimed was madness.
Was it Hamlet wronged,
Laertes?
No.
MIKE: Not even close.
- His madness
is poor Hamlet's enemy.
CROW:
I hate that "Our House" song,
you know.
MIKE:
Wow! That was the limpest,
wettest handshake ever.
- Give us the foils.
SERVO:
We shall some potatoes bake.
CROW:
Wow! That's not a widow's peak
that guy has,
it's a peninsula.
MIKE:
Alright, give me my gun.
[WHOOSHING]
SERVO:
Ooh, there's a bee! Ooh!
- This is too heavy.
Let me see another.
CROW:
Yeah, real smooth.
MIKE:
Hamlet's parents in the stand.
Give 'em a hand.
- If Hamlet hits...
SERVO: We'll do a sequel.
- ...let all the battlements
their ordnance fire.
The king shall drink
to Hamlet's better breath...
CROW:
Thank you, Corpse-io.
SERVO:
Here, sir.
- ...and in the cup
an union shall he throw,
richer than that which
four successive kings
in Denmark's crown
have worn.
MIKE:
Here, there's a little schmutz
on that.
- ...and let the kettle
to the trumpet speak...
SERVO:
Mmm hmm.
- ...the trumpet
to the cannoneer without,
the cannons to the heavens,
the heavens to earth.
Now the king drinks to Hamlet.
SERVO:
Hell, the king drinks
to anything.
CROW:
Glug, glug.
Ah! I got the worm.
- Come, begin, and you,
the judges, bear a wary eye.
MIKE:
Our celebrity judges
from the cast of Bay watch.
SERVO:
Alright, I'm gonna toss
the coin, Laertes.
If you will call?
MIKE:
Mmm-hmm.
SERVO: Huh.
MIKE: Mmm-hmm.
CROW:
Would you just fight?
[CLANKING]
MIKE:
And the round's over.
SERVO:
D'oh! Tsk.
Laertes immediately
bites his ear off.
[CLANKING]
CROW:
Wait, huh? Wait. What?
Catch... watch it.
Hey, hey!
None of that.
Wait!
[CLANKING]
- One?
- No.
- Judgment?
- A hit.
A palpable hit.
SERVO:
Hmm-hmm!
MIKE:
Well, what do you know?
A chance to drink!
[BOOM]
ALL: Aaugh!
SERVO:
A Finnish scud missile
just exploded.
[CLANKING]
CROW:
So, when do they start
selling stolen merchandise?
MIKE:
That's a different
kind of fencing.
CROW:
Oh, okay.
[CLANKING]
SERVO:
I am so baked. Ugh.
[CLANKING]
CROW:
There isn't a bad seat
in the arena.
You're right on top
of the action.
SERVO:
Mmm hmm.
- A hit on neither side.
MIKE:
Man, I'm Simon Le Bon.
SERVO:
Pssh. I suck.
- Stay!
SERVO: Hmm?
- Give me drink.
CROW:
You, give me drink too.
- Hamlet, this pearl is thine.
MIKE:
Sir, you dropped
a huge tablet in your cup.
- Here, to thy health.
SERVO:
Coming to a sudden end.
- I'll play this bout first.
CROW:
But it's cherry-flavored
kids' poison.
He should love it.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Hello everybody.
♪ Take me out
To the sword fight ♪
SERVO: [CHANTING]
We want a fencer,
not a belly... fencer...
[CLANKING]
- Another hit.
What say you?
- A touch, a touch.
I do confess it.
MIKE:
We are to be married.
CROW:
Let me have a go!
I'll fence your ass
back to the Stone Age.
- Come, Hamlet.
Let me wipe thy face.
SERVO:
I hope the next poison
is for me.
- Our son shall win.
MIKE:
Ooh, booze. Gimme.
- The queen carouses
to thy fortune, Hamlet.
CROW:
Whatever!
- Gertrude...
...do not drink!
SERVO:
What are you, stupid?
- I will, my lord.
I pray you, pardon me.
MIKE:
Ah, the queen's suicide fanfare.
SERVO:
♪ Daa daa daa ♪
Oh, so you didn't get
the poison memo, huh?
MIKE:
Ah, great.
Well, I'm not looking forward
to the Danish
singles' scene again.
- My lord, I'll hit him now.
SERVO:
Aw, forget it, Lame-ertes.
MIKE:
Boy, I drank a lot of that.
It was really good.
CROW:
Look, shut up.
SERVO:
Come on.
Bring it on, sweetmeat.
[TAPPING]
- Laertes, come!
You but dally.
I pray you,
pass with your best violence.
I'm afeard
you make a wanton of me.
- Say you so?
Come on.
CROW:
They're femme-cing.
[GASPS]
SERVO:
The royal Bactine!
MIKE:
That's cool.
CROW:
My nipple came off, you jerk!
[CLATTERING]
MIKE:
You've got pine tar on yours.
SERVO:
Uh, the king told me to.
MIKE:
Man, I'm hungry.
Oh.
CROW:
Yeah, see, see I don't trust
a sporting event done in
tights and puffy shirts.
MIKE:
Yeah.
SERVO:
And now my patented spaz move.
- Aiee!
CROW: Oh, hi.
- They bleed on both sides.
How is it, my lord?
MIKE:
Perhaps my impending baldness
can help.
- I'm justly killed
with mine own treachery.
CROW:
Don't eat the green sardines.
Bleh.
- How does the queen?
SERVO:
Oy! They call it DayQuil,
but still!
Hoo, boy!
- She swoons
to see them bleed.
- No, no.
The drink.
MIKE:
One last Old Fashioned
before I die.
- Oh, my dear Hamlet.
CROW:
The hair mold is in the...
uh!
- Hamlet!
SERVO: Get off your mom.
- Thou art slain.
No medicine in the world
can do thee good.
In thee there is not
half an hour's life.
The treacherous instrument
is in thy hand...
MIKE:
You mean, mom?
- ...unbated and envenomed.
Thy mother's poisoned.
I can no more.
The king's to blame.
The king.
CROW:
Long blame the king!
[CLATTERING]
- Envenomed.
SERVO:
Whoa! Just had that sharpened.
- Then, venom, to thy work.
MIKE:
You're under Danish arrest.
CROW:
Okay, okay.
Mistakes were made.
SERVO:
Uh-huh.
Now the king
peels off his skin
and becomes a dinosaur
from Mars!
CROW:
Yeah!
SERVO:
Or, I guess not.
MIKE:
Oh, come on, Hammy.
Hamster!
CROW:
Gee, the music!
Something's gonna happen.
I can't stand it!
It's really building up
to something!
Grrr!
That's it?
Wow.
- Defend me, friends.
I am but wounded.
[FOOTSTEPS]
- Here, incestuous, murderous,
damned Dane.
Drink off this potion.
MIKE:
Okay, better make out a will.
I, Claudius...
Ha ha ha!
I always tell that joke
when I'm dying.
CROW:
Hey, Hamlet.
Why don't you Ram-let?
SERVO:
Yeah? Shut up, Claudi-ass!
- Is thy union here?
MIKE:
Federation of Kings, Local 12?
- Follow my mother.
CROW:
She called for directions.
SERVO:
Ooh. Too bad
he's poison intolerant.
MIKE:
Check out our Pieta impression.
- Exchange forgiveness with me,
noble Hamlet.
SERVO:
Sure. You got a receipt?
Heh heh.
- Mine and my father's death
come not upon thee...
CROW:
Although,
you did stab him and all.
- ...nor thine on me.
SERVO:
Oh, let's have coffee next week.
Oh, yeah.
We'll be dead.
That's right.
- Heaven make thee free of it.
I follow thee.
MIKE:
Hold me, elongated Phil Collins.
[SIGHS]
SERVO:
He died with a booger
on his forehead.
MIKE:
You gonna be needing a second,
'cause my guy died, so...
CROW:
Well, we'll be seeking
volunteers to rule Denmark now.
SERVO:
I've been taking echinacea
and Vitamin C,
so I should be okay.
MIKE:
Cha! Who died and made you king?
- Horatio...
CROW:
You're standing on my foot.
- ...I am dead.
MIKE:
I had to work
through lunch today. Ugh.
- Had I but time...
SERVO:
I would've painted the garage.
- ...as this fell sergeant
death is strict in his arrest.
MIKE:
Sergeant Death.
He's WWF, right?
CROW:
Right.
- Oh, I could tell you...
CROW:
Is there a word
in the English language
he hasn't said?
- ...but let it be.
SERVO:
Wait, what was I talking about?
- Horatio...
MIKE:
What a stupid name.
- ...thou livest.
Report me and my cause.
CROW:
Yeah, the Globe crowd
is just waiting
for the bear-baiting to start.
- Never believe it.
Here's yet some liquor left.
- Thy hand, let go.
MIKE:
Whoo!
Thanks, 'cause it was really
kind of an empty gesture.
- What a wounded name, friend.
Things standing thus unknown
shall live behind me.
SERVO:
Mmm-hmm.
- If thou didst ever
hold me in thy heart...
CROW:
Right.
- ...in this harsh world
draw thy breath in pain...
CROW:
Yeah, yeah.
- ...to tell my story.
SERVO:
Okay, die now.
Boo! Boo!
You're dead.
You're dying now.
CROW: Boo! Boo! Die!
- Horatio...
SERVO:
And, dead!
MIKE:
Die!
CROW:
Rrargh!
- ...I am dead.
MIKE:
Forgot to do that paper.
I am so dead.
SERVO:
Maybe. I think...
CROW:
Aw, come on!
- ...fate...
SERVO:
Groundlings are all hitting
the exits by now.
CROW:
Boy!
- The rest is silence.
MIKE:
Yeah, I wish.
CROW:
Could be. What do you think?
SERVO:
I don't believe it.
CROW:
Deadness?
SERVO:
Yes.
CROW:
Have we achieved deadness?
Yo, Hamlet.
- Goodnight, sweet prince...
SERVO:
Night!
- ...and flights of angels
sing thee to thy rest.
CROW:
Unfortunately, they're Northwest
flights of angels,
so they'll be late.
SERVO:
Before you die, does my palm
smell like Cheetos?
MIKE:
You know,
they better get him out of there
before he melts, thaws,
and resolves himself
into a dew.
CROW:
Yeah, that can be a problem.
- Let four captains bear Hamlet
like a soldier to the stage,
CROW:
Captain Spaulding,
Captain Kangaroo,
Captain Crunch...
- ...for he was likely,
had he been put on,
to have proved most royal.
[♪♪♪]
SERVO:
Sounds like Mister Peabody's
about to start.
[♪♪♪]
[CROW HUMMING]
MIKE:
Hamlet will be back in
"Thunderball."
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
Well, Mike,
this has convinced me
not to kill your dad
and marry your mom.
[CHUCKLING]
SERVO:
Well, at least when the Germans
are doing this,
they can't be up to
any mischief.
[♪♪♪]
CROW:
So, spaetzle, the
Katzenjammer Kids, and this.
Thanks, Germany!
MIKE:
Hmm!
Filthy misogynist Paul Verhoeven
played the gravedigger.
What do you know?
SERVO:
♪ Doo doo doo doo
Doo doo doo doo doo ♪
CROW:
With Adolf
Schlyssenshyssenseddleschly
SERVO:
...der.
MIKE:
Danish consultant, Victor Borge.
SERVO:
Sardines courtesy King Oscar.
Look for special
"Hamlet" promotional cans.
CROW:
Also try Rosencrantz
and Guildenstern kipper snacks,
and Laertes
packed in heavy oil.
[♪♪♪]
MIKE:
Hey, I tell you,
between this movie
and the heating system
on the Volkswagen...
CROW:
Tch! Ick.
Gottschalk!
[SERVO HUMMING]
MIKE:
Thanks, Franz.
CROW:
Oh, yeah,
this was munchen all right. Huh!
MIKE:
Nice play, Shakespeare.
[GEARS GRINDING]
- So, you guys made
a Hamlet action figure, huh?
- Yup.
- Uh-huh.
- Anything remarkable about it?
Typical action figure?
You just kind of move it around,
that's the action?
- Yeah, that's about it.
- Pretty much.
- Well, you might want to
pull the string there.
- Oh, yeah.
- That's kind of nice.
- Oh, it talks.
- Uh-huh.
- Well, say.
Well, wow.
Kind of a long string.
- Well, that's what makes it
such a great action figure.
- Yeah.
- I know, but most action
figures with a string,
you know, you pull it,
it's like 18 inches long.
- It is a bit longer
on this one, I grant you.
- Mmm-hmm.
- Yeah, I know, but I mean,
it's really a lot longer.
- Well, Hamlet does have
some long speeches, Mike.
Oh, watch the umbrella stand.
- Ow! Ooh!
- Okay, keep going, honey.
It can't be too much more.
See, Mike, what I'd do
is go up those stairs there.
- Up the stairs, right.
- No, no, behind that.
MIKE:
I didn't even know
we had stairs here.
Never been over to this part
of the ship.
- Heh-heh.
MIKE:
Hey, how much longer is it?
- Not much!
Uh-oh. Uh-oh.
Pearl's calling.
MIKE:
I didn't know there was
a squash court up here.
- Yes, Pearl?
- Keep going.
- Look, I don't care
if you're small but pivotal.
You just can't waltz in here
and... hang on.
Hi, guys.
Got a little bit
of a situation here.
Apparently in Hamlet,
there's a character
named Fountainbras...
- Ah, it's Fortinbras.
- Yes.
- That's what I said.
- No, no, no,
actually you said...
Fortinbras.
- So, anyway he claims
he's in the original Hamlet
but he's not in this movie...
- Yes, and I'm not leaving
until I'm allowed
to play my role.
Am I simply
to hang about in limbo?
Or perhaps I should force myself
on another play, hmm?
Walk up to American Buffalo
and say,
"Hello, have you a need
for a Norwegian nobleman
to arrange for bodies
to be carted away?"
I don't think
I'm being unreasonable here.
- Play the part.
- Really?
- Sure. Go ahead.
Play the part.
- Well, I'll need
two English ambassadors.
- Will you?
- Yes, and the Horatio
and a band of soldiers
and drums at the beginning
and at the end
and a peal of ordnance
and, of course, a body.
- Oh, golly.
Where can I find a body
on such short notice? Hmm.
I wonder where.
Say, could you pour
this in your ear
for me for just a minute?
- Certainly.
- A body, a body...
[CHOKING]
Well, hey!
There's a body.
You're in luck.
Is it me?
Am I a magnet
for these idiots?
- He made me look butch.
SERVO:
Okay, let 'er go, Mike.
[♪♪♪]
- To be, or not to be:
that is the question.
Whether 'tis nobler in the mind
to suffer the slings and arrows
of outrageous fortune,
or to take arms
against a sea of troubles,
and by opposing end them?
To die; to sleep;
no more;
and by a sleep
to say we end the heart-ache
and the thousand natural shocks
that flesh is heir to,
'tis a consummation devoutly
to be wish'd.
To die,
to sleep.
To sleep,
perchance to dream.
Aye, there's the rub!